Dan McMahon

Web Developer

(312)810-9540

912 North Carlyle Lane Arlington Heights, IL 60004

danielrichardmcmahon@gmail.com

danmcmahondev.com

https://github.com/dmcmcmahon714

https://www.linkedin.com/in/danmcmahondev/

I'm a full stack web developer with experience in law, music, health & wellness. I see my role in the field as to help forge new creative frontiers in the tech industry. I am primarily driven to take on these roles by the hope for a more efficient, beautiful world. My varied experience of different industries gives me a unique approach to any challenge I am faced with. I also love people and figuring out the most efficient way to realize their visions. Overcoming the hurdles necessary to make dreams come to life is my greatest sense of satisfaction. My goal as a developer is my ability to blend the artistry of whoever I am working with and clean code to create the idyllic digital experience.

Technical Skills

- Full Stack Web Development:
 - Javascript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, MERN Stack, React.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SASS, Postgresql

Other Skills

- Communication
 - Public Speaking, Writing, Overall Human Interaction, Mindfulness

Experience

Example projects:

- Chicago Tow Find Public API app that allows users to find out if their cold got towed in Chicago
- <u>Pain Tracker</u> Users can track pain daily for accurate reporting history using this full stack application with authentication.
- Your Release Tracker Users enter and can track their favorite new music releases with this Ruby on Rails with React application.
- <u>absoluteJAMS</u> Full stack forum built all on rails designed for music discussion with authentication, likes, comments, and subject tags.
- <u>Gigglelibs</u> A fun mad lib generator for bored children and adults built with an Express/Mongoose backend with Node.js. The React front end was connected with CORS and was styled with React-Bootstrap.

Education

December 2019 - May 2020

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive

DePaul University, Chicago, IL - Communications - Journalism

Experience

April 2016-Present

Hot 8 Yoga, Los Angeles, CA - Registered Yoga Teacher

- Completed training in Yin, 26&2, and Hot Power Fusion Yoga Styles, led weekly workshops, membership sales
- Taught 750+ studio classes attended by 40+ recurring students and was hired for multiple private sessions

September 2015 - October 2016

JAKIMAC, Los Angeles, CA - Fashion Production, Copywriting

- Wrote product descriptions and other copy for the website of a solely online business
- Contributed to sales for vendors such as Nasty Gal and Urban Outfitters, manufactured garments by hand.

June 2010 - August 2015

Wiedner & McAuliffe, Ltd., Chicago, IL - Paralegal, Marketing Service

- Meticulously managed and exchanged files with experts/opposing counsel for \$1 million cases
- Authoring, formatting, and creating graphics for several successful business proposals to prospective clients
 December 2005-April 2008

Powerspace LLC (Fueled by Ramen/Atlantic Records), Global - Recording Artist, Performance

- Led band operations including web presence, merchandise design and contract negotiations. Performed 300+ concerts to thousands of fants
- Co-wrote and recorded an internationally released album which maintains 5000+ monthly listeners to this day